marchforourlives.com 2019-11-28

# Privacy Policy - March For Our Lives

**Effective Date:** March 2018

This Privacy Policy explains the privacy practices governing information collected through the March For Our Lives, Inc. website (the “ **Site** ”) owned and operated by March For Our Lives, Inc. (“ **MFOL** ,” “ **we** ,” “ **our** ” or “ **us** ”).

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully because when you submit information to or through the Site, you are consenting to the collection, processing and retention of your information as described in this Privacy Policy. Capitalized terms used but not defined herein have the meanings assigned to them in the [Terms of Use](https://marchforourlives.com/terms-of-use/).

If you do not agree with any part of this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Site.

##### INFORMATION WE COLLECT

**Information You Provide to Us.** When you use the Site, we or our service providers may collect information that could reasonably be used to contact you or to identify you personally, such as your name, email address, telephone number, mobile phone number or mailing address (“Personal Information”). You may also provide us with information when you submit User Content. Your User Content may be publicly available.

I **nformation We Collect Automatically.** Whenever you visit or interact with the Site, we may use a variety of technologies that automatically or passively collect information about how you access or use the Site (“ **Usage Information** ”). Usage Information may include your browser type, operating system, the page served, the time, and the preceding page views. However, this information does not identify you as an individual user. We do not treat Usage Information as Personal Information unless it is combined with other data that, once linked, can be used to identify you.

**Device Identifiers.** MFOL may also automatically collect your IP address or other unique identifier (“ **Device Identifie** r”) for the computer, mobile device, technology or other device (collectively, “ **Device** ”) you use to access the Site. A Device Identifier is a number that is automatically assigned to your Device when you access a web site or its servers, and our computers identify your Device by its Device Identifier. We may use a Device Identifier to, among other things, administer the Service, help diagnose problems with our servers, analyze trends, track users’ web page movements, help identify, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use.

**Cookies and Do Not Track.** We may collect information about you or your use of the Site through cookies, tracking pixels, mobile identifiers or other technologies. We use this information to better understand, customize and improve the Site, services and offerings as well as to manage our advertising. The information we collect through cookies, tracking pixels or mobile identifiers may help us understand how visitors use and engage with the Site. If you have provided us with your Personal Information, for example, when you registered for an account or requested information from us, we may associate this Personal Information with information we have collected through cookies, tracking pixels, mobile identifiers or other technologies.

**Cookies.** A “cookie” is a file that websites send to a visitor’s computer or other Internet-connected device to uniquely identify the visitor’s browser or to store information or settings in the browser. Your browser may tell you how to be notified when you receive certain types of cookies or how to restrict or disable certain types of cookies. Please note, however, that without cookies you may not be able to use all of the features of the Site. When you use the Site, neither we nor any third parties collect Personal Information about your online activities, over time or across third party websites. The Help section of your browser may tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting cookies. To find out more about cookies, visit [www.aboutcookies.org](https://www.aboutcookies.org/).

**Tracking Pixels.** A “tracking pixel” also known as an Internet tag, pixel tag, web beacon or clear GIF, links web pages to web servers and their cookies, and may be used to transmit information collected through cookies back to a web server.

**Do Not Track.** Currently the Site is not designed to respond to “Do Not Track” signals sent from your browser. For more information more about “Do Not Track,” please visit [www.allaboutdnt.org](http://www.allaboutdnt.org/).

##### HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION

Any information you submit on the Site may be used for a variety of purposes, including, for example, to:

  * respond to your questions and requests;
  * provide, maintain or improve the Site;
  * verify your identity;
  * request feedback or contact you about your use of the Site;
  * send you updates and newsletters or otherwise provide you with information about MFOL such as news about events, issues, resources or services;
  * organize volunteers or support for MFOL;
  * communicate with you;
  * monitor and analyze trends, usage and activities in connection with the Site;
  * carry out any other purpose for which we collected your information; or
  * in our discretion, to make changes to the Site or any of our policies

We will only use the information you provide to us in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Policy or where we have otherwise obtained your consent.

We may use your Personal Information to send you relevant promotions, personalized information, or updates or newsletters with information that you have requested or that may interest you.

##### HOW WE MAY SHARE YOUR INFORMATION

**Service Providers.** We may share your Personal Information with third parties that perform functions on our behalf (“ **Service Providers** ”) to carry out your requests, respond to your inquiries or make various features of the Site available to you. These Service Providers may help us to host or operate the Site, analyze data, provide customer service, conduct marketing, process payments or administer surveys or questionnaires.

**Partner Organizations.** We may share your Personal Information with like-minded organizations, candidates, groups or causes that we think may be of interest to you. We may also share your Personal Information with companies, organizations or individuals outside of MFOL when we have your consent to do so.

**Business Transfers.** We may share your information, including your Personal Information, with our parent company, or its subsidiaries and affiliates for internal reasons, primarily for business and operational purposes. We may share or transfer your information, including your Personal Information in connection with a merger, sale, acquisition, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution, bankruptcy or other change of ownership or control by MFOL or any affiliated company (in each case, whether in whole or in part).

**Legal Disclosure.** We may transfer and disclose information, including your Personal Information, to third parties to comply with a legal obligation, when we believe in good faith that the law requires it, at the request of governmental authorities conducting an investigation, to verify or enforce our Terms of Use, Privacy Policy or other applicable policies, to respond to an emergency or otherwise to protect the rights, property, safety, or security of the MFOL, third parties, visitors to the Site or the public.

##### YOUR PRIVACY CHOICES AND ACCESS

You may opt out of receiving email updates, newsletters or text messages by following the instructions in those emails or text messages, contacting us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#6313110a1502001a230e0211000b050c110c16110f0a1506104d000c0e). If you opt out, we may still send you other types of emails, such as those about your use of the Site or any donations or transactions.

If you wish to verify, correct, or update any of your Personal Information collected through the Site, you may contact us at the email or address included in the Contact Us section below. In accordance with our routine record keeping, we may delete certain records that contain Personal Information that you have submitted through the Site. We are under no obligation to store such Personal Information indefinitely and disclaim any liability arising out of, or related to, the destruction of such Personal Information. In addition, you should be aware that it is not always possible to completely remove or delete all of your information from our databases without some residual data because of backups or other technology-related reasons.

##### LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES

The Site may contain links to other sites, maintained by third parties. These links are provided only as a convenience to you. MFOL has no control over, and is not responsible for any content, products or services offered by or found on third party sites, or their privacy policies. Links to third party sites do not constitute an assumption of liability for or sponsorship, endorsement or approval of these sites or the content contained on these sites.

##### CHILDREN

We do not knowingly collect information from children under 13 years of age. If we learn that a child under the age of 13 has provided us with any Personal Information without first receiving their parent or guardian’s verified consent, we will use that information only to respond directly to that child (or his or her parent or legal guardian) to inform the child that he or she cannot use the Site. We will then dispose of such Personal Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. If you believe we may have any information from or about a child under the age of 13, please contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#c3b3b1aab5a2a0ba83aea2b1a0aba5acb1acb6b1afaab5a6b0eda0acae).

##### ACCESSING OUR SITE GLOBALLY – TRANSFER OF DATA

The Site is governed by and operated in, and in accordance with the laws of the United States. We make no representation that the Site is governed by or operated in accordance with the laws of any other nation. If you are located in the European Union, Canada or elsewhere outside of the United States, please be aware that information we collect may be transferred to and processed in the United States. By using the Site, or providing us with any information, you (a) acknowledge that the Site is subject to the laws of the United States, (b) consent to the collection, processing, maintenance and transfer of such information in and to the United States and other applicable territories in which the privacy laws may not be as comprehensive as or equivalent to those in the country where you reside and/or are a citizen, and (c) waive any claims that may arise under those laws.

##### YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS

We do not share your Personal Information with third parties for their marketing purposes without your consent.

##### SECURITY MEASURES

We use certain reasonable security measures to help protect your Personal Information. However, no electronic data transmission or storage of information can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Please note that we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us, and you use the Site and provide us with your information at your own risk.

##### CHANGES

We may update and post revisions to this Privacy Policy from time to time and will updated the Effective Date when we do so. If our Privacy Policy changes in a way that significantly affects how we handle your Personal Information, we will not use the Personal Information we currently maintain without providing you notice or obtaining your consent, where appropriate. We encourage you to review this page for the latest information about our privacy practices.

##### CONTACT US

If you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy, please contact us by email at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#1464667d6275776d54797566777c727b667b6166787d6271673a777b79).
